The software development life cycle is the process that will help the developer understand the steps they have to complete in order to finish the project. Its importance stems from its ability to break up the sections of software development to seperate stages of evaluation and creation. SDLC is a process followed for a software project, within a software organization. It consists of a detailed plan describing how to develop, maintain, replace and alter or enhance specific software.
